

CONTACT ME AT

- 3-5-118/2/3, Krishna Nagar,
 Hyderguda, Attapur,
 Hyderabad, Telangana State,
 India.
- skiran017@gmail.com
- +91 8789680086
- in @skiran017
- https://skiran017.github.io/portfolio/

SKILLS SUMMARY

- •••• React / Redux
- •••• Solidity, web3.js/ether.js
- •••• Webpack & Babel
- ●●●● NodeJS MongoDB
- •••• HTML5, CSS3/SCSS & JS
- •••• Next.js & Electron.js
- ••• Truffle, Infura

AWARDS RECEIVED

- Best Performer of the Month (March 2019)
- Research paper published:contact stresses distribution on Plunge-Cutting into a Steel Workpiece (Apr 2018).
- Research paper published :-Calculation of Contact Stresses distribution during titanium alloy cutting (Apr 2018).

SAI KIRAN SABAVATH

BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a Mechanical Engineer graduate, Research enthusiast and Lead UI engineer by profession with expertise in HTML/CSS, React, JavaScript and few other frontend technologies. I am also a blockchain developer and have built on Ethereum, Solana, NEAR, and most recently, Aptos. For my side projects, I work with Next.js, React-Native and basically with any other tech in JS Ecosystem. When I am not coding, I enjoy cooking, playing soccer and chess.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Founding Engineer

Amberley Tech| Dec 2022 - Current

- Maintaining and building the frontend projects.
- Providing performant solutions for project scalability.
- Occasionally contributing to backend projects.

Full Stack Developer

Alekhine Labs | Jun 2022 - Sept 2022

- I developed and maintained the frontend for a premium <u>Arbitoor</u> DEX Aggregator built on NEAR Protocol. I led the frontend development for <u>Imperi</u>-Token Vesting Platform built on Aptos.
- Tech stack: React/Redux, NextJS, Zustand, Webpack, Babel, TypeScript, Yarn/NPM, Vite.js, Chakra-UI, Material-UI, Styled-Components, Tailwind CSS.

Lead Software Engineer

Dhan Tech Labs India Pvt. Ltd | Jan 2021 - Jul 2022

- I built and maintained the frontend architecture of the products and various internal tools at Dhan.
- I led Frontend Engineering Team.
- I wrote Tests to ensure quality of the code being delivered.
- I did performance audits and optimizations to ensure great experience.
- Tech stack: React/Redux, Redux-Saga, React-Native, Ionic-React, Webpack, Babel, TypeScript, Yarn/NPM, Material-UI, Styled-Components, Zustand, MonoRepo.

Software Engineer

SSurya Immortal Power (OPC) Ltd. | Aug 2018 - Jan 2021

- Built and maintained the webapp for selling EPC products.
- Wrote APIs and maintained database.
- Implemented latest technologies like React and webpack to optimize the performance
- Tech stack: React.js, JavaScript, HTML5/CSS, REST APIs, MongoDB, Material-UI, webpack

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

Solana Tip-jar | NPM package

React, Chakra UI and @solana/web3.js - Github

 NPM package which users can integrate to send/receive tips in solana by connecting to their Phantom Wallet.

Multi-Sig Wallet | Ethereum

React with Chakra UI and web3.js - Github - Live

• Multi-Sig for Ethereum deployed on Kovan testnet.

Decentralized Exchange | ERC-20

React, Bootstrap and web3.js - Github - Live

 Decentralized Exchange for ERC-20 tokens built and deployed on Kovan testnet.

NFT Minter | Solana

React with Metaplex - Github - Live

 NFT Minter built using Metaplex Candy Machine and deployed on Solana Devnet.

NFT Marketplace | Ethereum

Next.js with three.js and web3.js - Github - Live

• NFT market place built on Ethereum and deployed on Rinkeby

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Tomsk Polytechnic University, Tomsk, Russia

Mechanical engineering | Sep 2014 - Jun 2018

- Specialization in Design and Manufacturing technologies
- ECTS: 4.63/5

Technical University of Ostrava, Ostrava, Czech Republic

Semester Exchange | Sep 2016 - Jan 2017

- CATIA, MATLAB, FEM
- ECTS: 4/5

Little Flower Junior College

Senior Secondary High School | June 2011 - April 2013

- Maths, Physics, Chemistry as Primary subjects
- Grade: A (78%)

Little Flower School

High School | CBSE | April 2011

• CGPA: 8.6/10